Guide to the Department of French, Yale University, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Department of French, Yale University, records
1920-1986
RU 424
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
79
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, minutes, audiotapes, films and videotapes documenting the activities of the Yale Department of French. Topics include faculty appointments, committee agendas, and methods of instruction.
Yale University. Dept. of French
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 14-B (YRG 14-B), Records of academic departments and programs of the Yale Faculty of Arts and Sciences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, memoranda, minutes, audiotapes, films and videotapes documenting the activities of the Yale Department of French. Topics include faculty appointments, committee agendas, and methods of instruction.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
French language -- Study and teaching; Universities and colleges -- Administration; Universities and colleges -- Departments; Audiotapes; Motion pictures (visual works); Photographs; Videotapes; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University -- Curricula; Yale University -- Faculty; Yale University. Dept. of French
- Records, 1920-1938; Accession 1938-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  The materials are open for research.
  - Faculty Appointments, 1924-1936 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committees, 1932-1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minutes of the Department of Romance Languages: Full and Associate Professors, 1920 January-29 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Records, circa 1962-1986; Accession 1990-A-154
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2021
  - Yale University Graduate School Student Records, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admissions
    - 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Offers, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Offers, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Offers, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Graduate School Affiliates, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Offers, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Applications: Admissions, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Admissions, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Acceptances, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Admissions, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Admissions Archives: General, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Admissions to Candidacy: First-Year Students, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Admissions to Candidacy: Second-Year Students, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Admissions, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Yale University Graduate School Student Records, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Yale University Graduate School Student Records, 1974-1976 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Courses
    - Enrollment, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Enrollment, 1973-1974 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Grades, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Grades, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Grades, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Grades, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - General, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - Grades, 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
    - Grades, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - Grades, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Dissertations: Readers" Reports
    - 1974 Dec (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1974 Apr (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1973 Dec (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 1973 May (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 1973 Feb (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 1972 Fall (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 1972 Spring (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - 1971 May (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - 1968-1969 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - 1967 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - 1966 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 43)
    - 1962-1964 (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - Financial Aid
    - 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Current Students
      - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - 1973-1974 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 51)
      - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 52)
    - Offers, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - Summer, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - Summer, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - Summer, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - M.A.T., 1958-1969 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - Applications: Refusals, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - Applications: Acceptances, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 59)
    - Applications, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - Admissions, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - Declining, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - Graduate School Diversity, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - Graduate and Professional Student Senate, 1971-1973 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - Bibliography, 1972 Fall (Box 2, Folder 65)
    - Courses: Bibliographies, 1971-1972 (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Yale-Cornell in Paris, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Romance Seminar: Library, 1954-1964 (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Archives: Prospectus, 1962-1975 (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Admissions Mailing, 1980 (Box 2, Folder 70)
    - Admissions, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 71)
    - Admissions Mailings, 1979 (Box 2, Folder 72)
    - Admissions Mailings, 1978 (Box 2, Folder 73)
    - Books, 1981 Spring (Box 2, Folder 74)
  - Books: Graduate
    - 1980 Fall (Box 2, Folder 75)
    - 1980 Spring (Box 2, Folder 76)
    - 1979 Fall (Box 2, Folder 77)
    - 1979 Spring (Box 2, Folder 78)
    - 1978 Fall (Box 2, Folder 79)
    - 1978 Spring (Box 2, Folder 80)
    - 1977 Fall (Box 2, Folder 81)
    - Book Lists, 1971-1976 (Box 2, Folder 82)
  - Course Descriptions and Schedules: Graduate
    - 1976-1978 (Box 2, Folder 83)
    - 1979-1980 (Box 2, Folder 84)
    - 1982 Spring (Box 2, Folder 85)
    - 1982 Spring (Box 2, Folder 86)
    - 1981 Fall (Box 2, Folder 87)
    - From Other Departments, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 88)
    - 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 89)
    - 1980-1981 (Box 2, Folder 90)
    - Job Search, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 91)
    - Job Search, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 92)
    - Job Search, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 93)
    - Job File, 1983-1984 (Box 2, Folder 94)
    - Job File, 1982-1983 (Box 2, Folder 95)
    - Job File, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 96)
    - Job Listing, 1981-1982 (Box 2, Folder 97)
    - Course Descriptions and Schedules, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 98)
    - Graduate Course Descriptions: Masters, 1976-1978, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 99)
    - Graduate Students in French, 1977-1981 (Box 3, Folder 100)
  - Graduate Studies Committee
    - 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 101)
    - 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 102)
    - 1976-1977 (Box 3, Folder 103)
    - 1974-1976 (Box 3, Folder 104)
    - 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 105)
    - 1965-1972 (Box 3, Folder 106)
  - Requirements and Regulations (Box 3, Folder 107)
    - 1978 May (Box 3, Folder 108)
    - 1977 May (Box 3, Folder 109)
    - 1976 Mar (Box 3, Folder 110)
    - 1975 Apr (Box 3, Folder 111)
    - Tutoring/Translating, 1979-1981 (Box 3, Folder 112)
    - Tutoring/ Translating, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 113)
    - Teaching: Graduate School Responses of Interest, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 114)
    - Books: Undergraduate, 1980 Fall (Box 3, Folder 115)
    - Books, 1980 Spring (Box 3, Folder 116)
    - Books: Undergraduate, 1980 Spring (Box 3, Folder 117)
    - Books: Undergraduate, 1979 Fall (Box 3, Folder 118)
    - Schedule, 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 119)
    - Graduate: French Reading Course, 1980 Spring (Box 3, Folder 120)
    - Course Schedule: Undergraduate, 1979 Spring (Box 3, Folder 121)
    - Course Schedule: Undergraduate, 1979 Fall (Box 3, Folder 122)
    - Enrollment, 1980 Spring (Box 3, Folder 123)
    - French 138: Materials, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 124)
    - Course Schedule: Undergraduate, 1978 Fall (Box 3, Folder 125)
    - Book Order: Undergraduate, 1978 Spring (Box 3, Folder 126)
    - Schedule, 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 127)
    - Syllabi, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 128)
    - Course Description and Schedules: Undergraduate, 1973-1978 (Box 3, Folder 129)
    - Enrollment, 1979 Fall (Box 3, Folder 130)
  - Enrollment: Undergraduate
    - 1979 Spring (Box 3, Folder 131)
    - 1978 Fall (Box 3, Folder 132)
    - 1978 Spring (Box 3, Folder 133)
    - 1977 Fall (Box 3, Folder 134)
    - 1971-1977 (Box 3, Folder 135)
    - Finals, 1980 Fall (Box 3, Folder 136)
    - Finals, 1981 Spring (Box 3, Folder 137)
    - Prizes Montaign, 1975-1979 (Box 3, Folder 138)
    - Prizes Scott, 1977-1979 (Box 3, Folder 139)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1977-1978 (Box 3, Folder 140)
    - Undergraduate Studies Committee, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 141)
    - Yale College Program of Studies, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 142)
    - Yale College Program of Studies, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 143)
    - Address Lists, 1978-1979 (Box 3, Folder 144)
    - Books: Publishers" Addresses, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 145)
    - Teaching Appointments, 1986-1987 (Box 3, Folder 146)
    - Faculty: French Department, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 148)
    - French Department, 1981-1982 (Box 3, Folder 149)
    - Faculty: Previous Years, 1973-1979 (Box 3, Folder 150)
  - French Embassy
    - General, 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 151)
    - General Correspondence, 1977, 1982, undated (Box 3, Folder 152)
    - Admission to French Universities, 1977, 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 153)
    - Employment in France, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 154)
    - Professeurs detaches, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 155)
    - Room Listings and Descriptions, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 156)
    - Office Machines, 1978-1982 (Box 4, Folder 157)
    - Budget Concerns, 1979-1982 (Box 4, Folder 158)
    - Maps, 1975-1980 (Box 4, Folder 159)
    - Services, undated (Box 4, Folder 160)
  - Report of Executive Committee, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 161)
  - Chronological: Director of Undergraduate Studies Miller
    - 1986 Spring (Box 4, Folder 162)
    - 1985 Fall (Box 4, Folder 163)
    - Yale Directory, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 164)
  - Chronological: Director of Undergraduate Studies
    - Miller, 1985 Spring (Box 4, Folder 165)
    - Miller, 1984 Fall (Box 4, Folder 166)
    - Burt, 1984 Spring (Box 4, Folder 167)
  - Chronological: Director of Graduate Studies
    - Guicharnaud, 1985 Spring (Box 4, Folder 168)
    - Guicharnaud, 1984 Fall (Box 4, Folder 169)
    - Guicharnaud, 1984 Spring (Box 4, Folder 170)
    - Guicharnaud, 1983 Fall (Box 4, Folder 171)
    - Chronological: Director of Undergraduate Studies Burt, 1983 Fall (Box 4, Folder 172)
  - Chronological: Administrative Assistant
    - J. Kahn, 1985 Fall (Box 4, Folder 173)
    - Kahn-Bender, 1986 Spring (Box 4, Folder 174)
    - Seidel, 1985 Spring (Box 4, Folder 175)
    - Seidel, 1984 Fall (Box 4, Folder 176)
    - Seidel, 1984 Spring (Box 4, Folder 177)
    - Seidel, 1983 Fall (Box 4, Folder 178)
    - Rodriguez, 1983 Fall (Box 4, Folder 179)
    - Miscellaneous: General Correspondence, 1982-1985, undated (Box 4, Folder 180)
    - Language Teaching Methodology Course, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 181)
    - Statistics: Graduate, Undergraduate, Faculty, etc., 1971-1982 (Box 4, Folder 182)
    - Applicants from Minority Schools, 1975-1982 (Box 4, Folder 183)
- French sound archives collected by Pierre Capretz, 1959-1983; Accession 2001-A-152
  Original audiovisual materials, as well as preservation and duplicating masters, may not be played. Researchers must consult use copies, or if none exist must pay for a use copy, which is retained by the repository. Researchers wishing to obtain an additional copy for their personal use should consult Copying Services information on the Manuscripts and Archives web site.
  - French Songs for Background Music (Box 1)
  - Plastic Bertrand Sings (Box 1)
  - Pierre: Aspirations et besoins du monde actuel (Box 1)
  - Allais, A.: Selections read by Robert Rocca (Box 1)
  - Anouilh, J.:
    - Humulus le muet, excerpts (Box 1)
    - Le Petit Moliere (Box 1)
    - Medee (Box 1)
  - Apollinaire, G.:
    - Film on Apollinaire (Box 1)
    - Poems read by J. Duby (Box 1)
    - Poems (Box 1)
    - Poems read by Maurice Escande (Box 1)
    - Poems (Box 1)
    - "Le Pont Mirabeau" (Box 1)
  - St. Exupery, A. de: Terre des hommes, excerpts read by Mme Bataillard (Box 1)
  - Arnoux, A.: Le Chevalier errant (Box 1)
  - Audiberti, J.: Quoat, Quoat (Box 1)
  - Ayme, M.:
    - La Carte (Box 1)
    - Contes du chat perche (Box 1)
    - Dermuche (Box 1)
    - La Tete des autres, excerpts Act II, sc. 12 (Box 1)
  - Balzac, H. de
    - La Femme abandonnee (Box 1)
    - La Messe de l'athee (Box 1)
    - Paris-Balzac (Box 1)
  - Barthes, R.: Actualite de la rhetherique (Box 1)
  - Baudelaire, C.
    - Dieu et Satan, by Imbrie Buffum (1 of 2), 1956 November 20; 1; 2 audiotapes (reel-to-reel) (Box 2, Reel F-0-36)
    - Dieu et Satan, by Imbrie Buffum (2 of 2), 1956 November 20; 1 (Box 2, Reel F-0-37)
    - Baudelaire, Critique (1 of 2), by Jean Boorsch, 1967 November 14; 1 (Box 2, Reel F-0-38)
    - Baudelaire, Critique (2 of 2), by Jean Boorsch, 1967 November 14; 1 (Box 2, Reel F-0-39)
    - Le Peintre et le Poete (ou Baudelaire et Delacroix) (Box 2)
    - Poems read by Jean Marchat (Box 2)
    - Collected Poems (Box 2)
    - Poems II, read by various people (Box 2)
    - Poems III, read by Jean Dessailly (Box 2)
    - Poems IV, Les Fleurs du mal, read by L. Jourdan and E. Le Gallie (Box 2)
    - Poems V, read by various people (Box 2)
    - Poems VI, read by J.L. Barrault and J. Vilar (Box 2)
    - Poems VII, read by various people (Box 2)
    - Poems VIII (Box 2)
    - "Les Bijoux" (Box 2)
    - "Le Mauvais Vitrier" (Box 2)
    - Poems I, read by Peirre Viala (Box 2)
  - Barrault, J.L.: Profession de foi du comedien (Box 2)
  - Bayard: Le Chevalier Bayard (Box 2)
  - De Roby: Les Animaux et les hommes (Box 3)
  - Beaumarchais, de: Le Mariage de Figaro (Box 3)
  - Beaumarchais, de: Le Mariage de Figaro, (C.F.) 5 Acts, one/tape (Box 3)
  - Beauvoir, S. de Une Histoire que je me racontais (Box 3)
  - Beckett, S. En Attendant Godot (Box 3)
  - Herval; Dumas: Merval: Aurelia; Dumas: Le Square, expt. (Box 3)
  - Beckett, S. Oh, les beaux jours, read by Madeleine Renaud (Box 3)
  - Beckett, S.: Le Theatre de Samuel Beckett, by J.J. Mayoux (Box 3)
  - Hugo, Mallarme; Toulet, Lemartine: Poetry Reading and Commentary, by Paul Benichou (Box 3)
  - Bernanos, G.: Dialogues des Carmelites (Box 3)
  - Bodoin, J. La Table de multiplication (Box 3)
  - Bonnefoy, Y.: Poemes, dits a Yale, 1960 (Box 3)
  - Borel, J.: Reads exerpts from L'Adoration (Box 3)
  - Butor, H.: Le Roman et la Poesie (Box 3)
  - Camus, A.: Albert Camus le romancier, by G. Bree (Box 3)
  - Camus, A.: Reading Combat (Box 3)
  - Mauriac, F.: Reading Le Figaro (Box 3)
  - Malraux, Camus: The Crisis of Modern Man as Seen by Malraux and Camus, by H. Peyre (Box 3)
  - Camus, Albert
    - La Chute (Box 4)
    - Reading excerpts from La Chute and La Peste (Box 4)
    - Reading excerpts from La Chute (Box 4)
    - His Voice and His Works (Box 4)
    - Reading excerpts from L'Etranger (Box 4)
    - Reading excerpts from L'Etranger and L'Ete (Box 4)
    - Excerpts from L'Etranger (Box 4)
    - Excerpts from L'Etranger (Box 4)
    - La Femme adultere from L'Exil et le royaume (Box 4)
    - L'Hote (Box 4)
    - Archeologie de Paris, interview de Patrick Perrin (Box 4)
    - Pierre Boulez directeur du Centre de Recherche de Musique Electro-Acoustique (Box 4)
    - Dixieme anniversaire de la mort d'Edith Piaf (Box 4)
    - Exposition en hommage a Paul Poiret (Box 4)
    - Attribution du Prix Louis Delluc a B. Tavernier (Box 4)
    - Interview avec Bernard Lavalette (Box 4)
    - Francoise Christophe (Box 4)
    - Interview avec Pierre Etienne Heymann (Box 4)
    - Les Muets from L'Exil et le royaume (Box 4)
    - Les Muets from L'Exil et le royaume (Box 4)
    - French poetry read by Jean Gaudon (Box 4)
    - Le Pret-a-porter, interview with various dress designers (Box 4)
  - Carco, F.: Le Temps de la boheme (Box 4)
  - Celine, L.F.: His Voice and His Works (Box 4)
  - Cendars, B.: Les Paques a New York (Box 4)
  - Chateaubriand, F.: Selections from Atala, Rene, Memoires d'outre-tombe, Itineraire de Paris a Jerusalem (Box 4)
    - Recordings for Children (Box 4)
  - Laclos, C. de: Les Liaisons dangereuses, by Fabre (Box 4)
  - Claudel, P.:
    - Paul Claudel (Box 4)
    - Presentation de Claudel, by J.L. Barrault (Box 5)
    - His Voice and His Works (Box 5)
    - Christophe Colomb (Box 5)
    - Jeanne au bucher (Box 5)
    - L'Echange (Box 5)
    - L'Otage in 3 Acts (Box 5)
    - Tete d'or, excerpts (Box 5)
  - Cocteau, J.:
    - Discours de reception a l'Academie Francaise (Box 5)
    - La Voix bumaine (Box 5)
    - La Voix bumaine, 2 interpretations: G. Morlay; B. Bovy (Box 5)
    - Les Maries de la Tour Eiffel (Box 5)
    - Les Parents terribles (Box 5)
    - Orphee, read by J. Cocteau (Box 5)
    - His Voice and His Works (Box 5)
  - Colette, S.: (Box 5)
  - Her Voice and Her Works (Box 5)
    - Le Ble en berbe (Box 5)
    - Le'Enfant et les sortileges (Box 6)
    - Gigi, Cheri, Flore et Pomone, reading selections (Box 6)
    - Reading from Journal, La Femme cachee, La Paix (Box 6)
  - Contant, M.: Le Joueur de flute (Box 6)
  - Conversations (Box 6)
    - Orientation professionnelle (Box 6)
  - Le Corbusier: Mes Pensees a 73 ans (Box 6)
  - Corneille, P.: Le Heros cornelien, by Andre Stegmann (Box 6)
    - Le Cid, selections (C.F.) (Box 6)
    - Le Cid (T.N.P.) 5 Acts, one/tape (Box 6)
    - Cinna, excerpts (Box 6)
    - Horace, excerpts (Box 6)
  - (Curie): Monsieur et Madame Curie, documentary (Box 6)
  - Dac, P.: Le Nomme Antonin… (Box 6)
  - d'Annunzio, G.: Le Martyre de Saint Sebastian (Box 7)
    - Contes de mon moulin (Box 7)
    - Le Cure de Cucugnan (Box 7)
    - Les Trois messes basses (Box 7)
    - Tartarin de Tarascon (Box 7)
  - de Gaulle, C.: De la France libre a la Veme Republique, 1940, 1950, 1958, 1958-59 (Box 7)
  - Descartes, R.: Visages de Descartes, by Jean Conilh (Box 7)
  - Devos, R.: Au Theatre des varietes (Box 7)
    - Le Francais conscient (Box 7)
  - Verne, J.: Science and Literature: Jules Verne, by Michel Serres (Box 7)
  - Sartre, J.P.: Le Mur (Box 7)
  - Marker, C. Le Joli mai (Box 7)
  - Diderot, D. Le Neveu de Rameau, reading selections (Box 7)
    - Le Neveu de Rameau (Box 7)
  - Donnay, M. Leurs Debuts, read by Pierre Bertin and Max des Rieux (Box 7)
  - Doubrowsky, M. Litterature classique et critique contemporaine (Box 7)
  - Beckett, S. Fin de partie (R.T.F.) (Box 7)
  - Duras, M. Un Barrage contre le Pacifique; expt: Moderate Cantabile (Box 7)
  - Ionesco, E. La Lecon, excerpts from Le Naufrage; Le Rhinoceros (Box 7)
  - Camus, A. Le Malentendu, excerpts - an intro. In English (Box 8)
    - XVII Century: Pre-classical Poets (Box 8)
  - Dufilho, J. Histoires et monologues (Box 8)
  - Dufilho, J. Histoires de rire (Box 8)
  - Duhamel, G. Histoires (Box 8)
  - Dumas, A. Les Trois Mousquetaires (Box 8)
  - D. de Segonzac. Dunoyer de Segonzac (Box 8)
  - Duras, M. Marguerite Duras parle: Elle a vendu son enfant (Box 8)
  - Ehrmann, J. Histoire, tragedie et utopie (Box 8)
  - Eisenhower, D. Eisenhower a Paris, radio reception, 1959 September (Box 8)
  - Eluard, P. Poems read by Geard Philipe (Box 8)
    - Poems read by Daniel Ivernel (Box 8)
  - Emmanuel, P. Poems read by the author (Box 8)
    - Lecture by the author (Box 8)
  - Ferdinand, R.
    - Les J3 by D. Joubert and J. Gaudillere on film L'Air du temps (Box 8)
    - L'Air du temps, film on Montpellier (Box 8)
    - Visages de l'Algerie (Box 8)
  - Balzac
    - L'Auberge rouge (Box 8)
    - L'autre face de la lune (Box 8)
  - Renoir, J. La Caporal epingle based on novel by J. Perret (Box 8)
  - Sartre, J.P. La Chambre (RTF)
    - Chasses de Neptune, doc sur la peche sous-marine (Box 9)
    - Le Dernier matin d'Andre Chenier (Box 9)
  - Chabrol, C. Les Cousins (Box 9)
  - Queffelec. Dieu a besoin des hommes, from novel: Un Recteur de l'Ile de Sein by Queffelec (Box 9)
  - Moliere. Don Juan (dir. By Eluval - O.R.T.F.) (Box 9)
    - Douceur du villiage, dir. By F. Reichenbach (Box 9)
  - Melville, J.P. Le Doulos, by Henri Peyre (Box 9)
    - Le Doulos, screenplay based on novel by Pierre Lesou (Box 9)
  - Bedos, G. and Baratier, J. Dragees au poivre (Box 9)
    - Eleves et champions, documentary (Box 9)
  - Ehrmann, J. Cinema, realites, verite (Box 9)
  - Gillet, A. Equilibre, doc.on Gothic architecture (Box 9)
    - La Famille de Broglie, (Les Grandes familles francaises) (Box 9)
  - Fautrier, J. Fautrier l'enrange, documentary (Box 9)
  - Galy, J.P. La Fete foraine (Box 9)
    - Francaise 63, doc. on women and womanhood in France (Box 9)
  - Marshan, B and J. Les Fruits de l'ete (Box 10)
    - Godard, J. L. (Box 10)
    - A Bout de souffle (Box 10)
    - Des Hommes dans le ciel, doc. on art of parachuting (Box 10)
    - Au Coeur de l'Ile de France, doc on the arts (Box 10)
    - Les Impresionnistes, doc on school of painting (Box 10)
    - Les Inconnus de la Terre, doc on peasants of neglected region of Cevennes (Box 10)
  - Laclos, C. de. Les Liaisons dangereuses, lec on film on film by J. Ehrmann (Box 10)
  - Baclos, C. de. Les Liaisons dangereuses, S.P. and dir by Roger Vadim (Box 10)
  - Sartre, J.P. Les Mains sales, lec on film by Jean-Pierre Morel (Box 10)
    - Les Mains sales (Box 10)
    - Martin et Gaston (Box 10)
  - Clair, R. Le Million, dir by Rene Clair (Box 10)
  - Moliere. Les Misanthrope, French T.V. production by J.J. Cornu (Box 10)
    - Montagnes mariques, (film on the Pyrenees) (Box 10)
    - Musique de films: excerpts from Les Jeux interdits, L'Eau vive, Les Visiteurs du soir (Box 10)
    - Nous entrerons dans la carriere, doc on problems of French youth in a provincial villa (Box 10)
    - D'Or et de diamant, doc on art of jewelry making (Box 10)
  - Cocteau, J. Introductory talk to Orphee by J. Guicharnaud (Box 11)
    - Orphee, written and dir by J. Cocteau (Box 11)
    - Pain blanc, pain noir, doc on food industry in Paris (Box 11)
  - Clert, C. Paris des cinq continents, doc on Paris as cultural, social and economic world center (Box 11)
  - Gibaud, M. La Ballade parisienne, doc history of old Paris (Box 11)
  - Preyert, P. Paris la belle (Box 11)
  - Condroyes. Paris-flash, animated cartoon of tourists visiting Paris (Box 11)
    - Une Ville qu'on appelle Paris, doc on Paris (Box 11)
  - Cocteau, J. Pauvre Matelot, melodrama (Box 11)
    - Les Peintres romans, doc on French Romanesque painting (Box 11)
    - Images du Perigord, doc on Perigord Province (Box 11)
  - Colson/Malleville. Pierre de lune, animated cartoon (Box 11)
    - La Pierre-St. Martin, doc on spelunking in the Pyrenees (Box 11)
  - Victor, P. E. Les Pingouins, doc on complete life cycle of the Penguins (Box 11)
  - Ophuls, M. Le Plaisir (Box 11)
    - Plein-air, documentary on group of boys and girls camping, sailing, climbing on the Basque coast (Box 11)
    - Le Poulet, short story of a boy and his pet rooster (Box 11)
    - La Promenade de Versailles, doc on the Palace of Versailles (Box 11)
  - Renoir, J. La Regle du jeu, scenario, dialogue and direction by J. Remoir (Box 11)
    - La Republique nous appelle, documentary on mountainn climbing techniques (Box 11)
    - La Route des Indes, documentary on history, communication between Europe and East Indies (Box 11)
  - Cocteau, J. Ruy Blas, introduction to the film by Jean Boorsch (Box 11)
    - La Sang d'un poete, intro to film by Jacques Guicharnaud (Box 11)
    - Le Sang d'un poete (Box 11)
    - L'Histoire de Paris: Les Peintres, la Mode printemps-ete (Box 11)
    - Thaumetopoea, documentary on life cycle of a species of caterpillar (Box 11)